PAVAN KUMAR SETTEM

SALESFORCE DEVELOPER

9480086653 | settempavan@gmail.com | Bengaluru, Karnataka, INDIA |

CAREER SUMMARY

Around 13+ years of professional experience, including 9+ years in IT, with 5+ years as a Salesforce CRM Developer and Administrator, and 4+ years as a Python Back-End Developer.

Easily adaptive to constantly changing technologies and challenges posed by evolving technologies, to suit business needs.

Strong analytical and problem-solving skills to investigate complex issues.

Excellent analytical, Written and oral communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Salesforce CRM Developing and Administering
- APEX Development
- Lightning Web Component (LWC)
- Process Automation (Flow, Workflow rules)
- Python Programing
- Web technologies: HTML, JavaScript, CSS
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, SDLC
- Repository: GIT
- Project Tracking: JIRA, Confluence

WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE SALESFORCE DEVELOPER — Self-Employed

Nov 2023 - Present

- Worked on various features like SOQL, Page Layouts, Record Types, Apex classes, Apex Triggers, Batch class, Custom Metadata, Workflows, Validation Rules and Flows.
- Developed custom Apex triggers and Lightning pages to automate business processes and enhance user experience.
- Collaborated with clients to gather requirements, translate business needs into technical solutions, and deliver projects on time.

QUEST GLOBAL, BANGALORE — Senior Salesforce Developer

May 2022 - Oct 2023

- Created new Custom objects, fields, Custom tabs, Components.
- Customized application using Apex Classes, Asynchronous process, apex test classes, Triggers, Lightning web components and Lightning Pages.
- Implementation of various advanced features like Custom Formula Fields, Validation Rules, Work Flows, Flows and Sharing rules to meet business requirements.
- Performed configuration and customization according to the Business requirements in Custom Buttons,
 Custom Settings, Email Templates.
- Migrating the Components between different orgs using version control and deployment tools.

ESCORTS, DELHI (NCR) — Senior Salesforce Developer

Sept 2020 - Apr 2022

- Worked on various features like SOQL, Page Layouts, Record Types, Apex classes, Apex Triggers, Batch class, Custom Metadata, Workflows, Validation Rules and Flows.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications as per business requirement.
- Provided post-implementation support involving fixing issues, implementing enhancement requests and administrative tasks.
- Adopted to Agile methodology and worked effectively.

TECHNIPFMC, HYDERABAD — Salesforce Developer

Aug 2019 - June 2020

- Created new Custom objects, fields, Custom tabs, Components.
- Customized application using Apex Classes, Asynchronous process, apex test classes, Triggers, Lightning web components.
- Migrating the Components from Sandbox to Production and testing Org using Change sets.
- Adopted to Agile methodology and worked effectively.

TECH MAHINDRA, HYDERABAD — Senior Engineer

Dec 2018 - Jul 2019

- This project involves data analysis and web scraping techniques for stock market websites.
- Involved in developing python code for business logic.
- Developing scripts to reduce time and manual effort.
- Creating tools according to Client requirements.
- Writing logics according to the URL provided and data to be scrapped.

CYIENT, HYDERABAD — Senior Engineer

Jul 2011 - Dec 2018

Atom is a kind of Application performance monitoring tool with chatops feature. With design thinking I developed this whole project from scratch.

- Implemented Design thinking and started the product from scratch.
- Designing of HTML pages for the entire application.
- Involved in writing scripts for ChatOps and Monitoring features in tools.
- Creating and Maintaining database for users.
- Debugging code depending on error codes which we created internally.

VPI, PUNE — Design Engineer (Mechanical)

May 2010 - Jul 2011

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Technology — Madina Engineering College (JNTU Ananthapur), Kadapa, Andhra Pradesh, INDIA.

MAY 2005 - APRIL 2009